<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Cristhian</title>
    <link>https://crisortiz92.github.io/landing-page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Cristhian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://crisortiz92.github.io/landing-page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 5: Customer Segmentation Using K Means Clustering (data from CRM)</title>
      <link>https://crisortiz92.github.io/landing-page/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crisortiz92.github.io/landing-page/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Objetives   Through the extraction of information from a CRM created in wordpress using the Jetpack CRM plugin perform customer segmentation by clusters.
  This use case is very common and it is used in BFS industry(credit card) and retail for customer segmenattion.
  Link to GitHub Repository
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: DCE for Water Resource Conservation</title>
      <link>https://crisortiz92.github.io/landing-page/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crisortiz92.github.io/landing-page/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>The case study is centered on the understanding of farmers&#39; preferences and livestock practices in Mejia. The aim behind determining their preferences is to find out which is the preferred way to tackle the issue of animal and solid waste pollution, water inefficiency, and conflicts over water use. For the econometric analysis, a mixed logit model in willingness to pay (WTP) was employed. Our findings can provide policymakers with information on priorities and ways to improve agricultural subsidies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Procesamiento de lenguaje natural</title>
      <link>https://crisortiz92.github.io/landing-page/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crisortiz92.github.io/landing-page/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Caso práctico  Objetivo del análisis Analizar los tópicos y palabras más usadas en 3 medios Ecuatorianos (El Comercio, El Universo y Primicias) al referirse al término de búsqueda Andres Arauz y Rafael Correa Web Scraping El presente trabajo se basó en la obtención de las noticias de dichos medios a través de web scraping utilizando R. Script de R La estructuración y pre-procesamiento de los datos se encuentra disponible en el código adjunto archivo “Complete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: ML model using Python </title>
      <link>https://crisortiz92.github.io/landing-page/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crisortiz92.github.io/landing-page/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Caso práctico  Objetivo del análisis Clasificación y predicción de los grupos con alto riesgo de suicidio a nivel mundial En este trabajo se investigo. si varias características como: la edad, el sexo, la población, entre otras. Tienen poder de clasificación para identificar grupos de alto riesgo, esto esto con miras de poder prevenir suicidios y proponer planes de contingencia conociendo los grupos prioritarios a intervenir.    Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: Estimación del crecimiento del PIB en Brasil utilizando ECM </title>
      <link>https://crisortiz92.github.io/landing-page/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crisortiz92.github.io/landing-page/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Caso práctico  Objetivo del análisis Utilizar el modelo de corrección de errores (ECM) para estimar el crecimiento anual del PIB en Brasil en el periodo de 1975 a 2013 La guía utilizada en esta práctica fue obtenida del paper “Early estimates of GDP growth rates by error correction models”, en nuestro caso utilizamos los datos anuales del Banco Mundial para Brasil.    Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://crisortiz92.github.io/landing-page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crisortiz92.github.io/landing-page/contact/</guid>
      <description>Follow me on these social media platforms.
   Platform URL     Medium: https://medium.com/@cris.ortiz1992/   GitHub: https://github.com/crisortiz92   RPubs: https://rpubs.com/crisruso23/    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
